Welcome to the Gmail API OAuth Verification Demo for TradeSphere Global.
Developed by KrisLynx LLP, a part of RKLS Groups Pvt. Ltd.
This video demonstrates how our platform securely uses the Gmail API `gmail.send` scope.
OAuth Client ID: 114692921129511160415
Let’s walk through the real use case of how our users interact with the Gmail API.
The user logs into TradeSphere Global using their Google account on our secure dashboard.
Upon clicking the “Send Email Page” button, the user is redirected to the email composer screen.
Here, the user enters recipient email, subject, message body, and optionally attaches a file.
Once ready, they click “Send Email” to trigger the Gmail API authentication flow.
Google’s OAuth screen is shown, and the user selects their Gmail account to continue.
The consent screen appears, requesting the `gmail.send` permission only.
After the user grants permission, the email is sent from their Gmail account using our system.
The user immediately sees a success confirmation inside our app dashboard.
To ensure transparency, the user can also check their Gmail "Sent" folder.
The email appears as if they sent it directly from their Gmail account.
Additionally, we log this email event inside the app’s “Sent Email” section.
No Gmail content is stored, and we never access or read user inboxes.
We only use `gmail.send` to send user-initiated messages with their full consent.
Tokens are encrypted and scoped per session. No token is stored persistently.
This implementation is fully compliant with Google’s API Services User Data Policy.
We respect user privacy, and no data is sold, shared, or used outside intended scope.
Our app ensures that users stay in control of what is sent from their account.
Thank you for reviewing the OAuth implementation of TradeSphere Global by KrisLynx LLP.